<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>personal on { always: &#39;coding&#39; }</title>
    <link>https://alwayscoding.ca/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in personal on { always: &#39;coding&#39; }</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:45:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alwayscoding.ca/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making life easier or at least better - Five month Baby recap</title>
      <link>https://alwayscoding.ca/momentos/2022/02/07/making-life-easier-or-at-least-better-five-month-baby-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alwayscoding.ca/momentos/2022/02/07/making-life-easier-or-at-least-better-five-month-baby-recap/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m in no way partnered with any brands mentioned nor are any of the links referrals. They&amp;rsquo;re simply links to products I used.
 We had our first child five months ago. A beautiful little boy- Remi. We&amp;rsquo;re lucky enough to have good friends around us who have also recently had children and we received lots of baby clothes, toys, and items donated or on loan.
This post is written not with any advice in mind, but around some of the reptitive tasks we do daily and items we found useful each day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your career is fine without working for big companies</title>
      <link>https://alwayscoding.ca/momentos/2022/01/19/your-career-is-fine-without-working-for-big-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 12:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alwayscoding.ca/momentos/2022/01/19/your-career-is-fine-without-working-for-big-companies/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about this numerous times over the course of my career and it is something I want to share. This is for the junior and intermediate developers out there who spend time visiting conferences, reading blogs, listening to podcasts, and doing their best to hone their craft. The developers who week after week take in content from industry influencers talking about the big projects they&amp;rsquo;ve worked on at BigCompany. Maybe you have thought about what it would feel like to work on similar big projects and experience growth in the industry like them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling New Years Resolution Complete!</title>
      <link>https://alwayscoding.ca/momentos/2020/11/24/cycling-new-years-resolution-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 23:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alwayscoding.ca/momentos/2020/11/24/cycling-new-years-resolution-complete/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve missed my cycling goals two years in a row. Should I tone back my expectations or is that under-aiming?  @brian_pearce https://twitter.com/brian_pearce/status/561380088168468481   Only 5 years later. I decided to have the same goal &amp;amp; New Years resolution for 2020. Complete 10,000km of cycling and tonight I completed it a month early!
Highlights Despite the Pandemic kicking off I made good use of our 12 week real lockdown in Barcelona.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RustFest 2016 - Learning to Love the Unfamiliar</title>
      <link>https://alwayscoding.ca/momentos/2016/11/16/rustfest-2016-learning-to-love-the-unfamiliar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alwayscoding.ca/momentos/2016/11/16/rustfest-2016-learning-to-love-the-unfamiliar/</guid>
      <description>Coming from Ruby, JS, Python or another language? Exploring new languages can be toilsome. Rust is no different. You’ll find new idioms and features that could be unfamiliar to navigate. You might even detest them at first; comparing it to how you’d prefer it in your favourite language.
We will learn to navigate your transition into the Rust landscape. Introduce practices that might not make sense at first. See comparisons of how you may have done things, and how we can improve those practices with Rust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacBook Air (Mid 2013) Wifi Issues</title>
      <link>https://alwayscoding.ca/momentos/2013/09/17/macbook-air-mid-2013-wifi-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 20:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alwayscoding.ca/momentos/2013/09/17/macbook-air-mid-2013-wifi-issues/</guid>
      <description>As soon as the MacBook Air (Mid 2013) started shipping; reports began flooding in about intermittant wifi connectivity problems.[1] The day after it was released I ordered it. I can&amp;rsquo;t say I experinced the same issues everyone else was claiming to run into. Apple denied the issue at first (as they always do) but later released a software update for the issue.[2]
Not soon after the software update I began experiencing the wifi connectivity issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meaning in my work</title>
      <link>https://alwayscoding.ca/momentos/2013/09/10/meaning-in-my-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alwayscoding.ca/momentos/2013/09/10/meaning-in-my-work/</guid>
      <description>“If you enjoy what you do you will never work a day in your life.”      Just recently I was elated when a client contacted us. We have been working on an ongoing project with them for over two years. They contacted us just to let us know they had used the project as a demo and witness. They used the project to help acquire funding for twenty-five full scholarships for youth from all over the world to attend any educational insitutue of their choosing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Drive 100km to Abbotsford from Vancouver for a Meetup</title>
      <link>https://alwayscoding.ca/momentos/2013/02/06/why-i-drive-100km-to-abbotsford-from-vancouver-for-a-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alwayscoding.ca/momentos/2013/02/06/why-i-drive-100km-to-abbotsford-from-vancouver-for-a-meetup/</guid>
      <description>In 2009 I attended Wordcamp Vancouver and actually met a handful of people I still talk to, tweet to and hang out with on a semi-regular basis. At the Wordcamp after party I was talking with @curtismchale and he mentioned although he didn&amp;rsquo;t do much ruby development he got together with the Fraser Valley Ruby Brigade on Wednesday nights in Abbotsford. He also mentioned they hang out on irc frequently and I should pop into the channel and say Hi.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
